♪No one left to lean on♪
♪لم يبق أحد يمكن الاعتماد عليه♪
♪No way out, no place to run♪
♪لا مخرج، لا مكان للهروب♪
♪Tears held back inside my eyes♪
♪الدموع محصورة في عيني♪
♪I run against the wind and time♪
♪أركض ضد الريح والوقت♪
♪Loved and lost, regrets remain♪
♪ محبوبون وضائعون، والندم يبقى ♪
♪But tears fall down like gentle rain♪
♪ولكن الدموع تسقط مثل المطر اللطيف♪
♪I look up strong, I grow with pride♪
♪أنظر إلى الأعلى بقوة، وأنمو بفخر♪
♪Living life with heart untied♪
♪عيش الحياة بقلب غير مقيد♪
♪Holding tight♪
♪التمسك بقوة♪
♪The burning faith you gave♪
♪الإيمان المتقد الذي أعطيته♪
♪Healing wounds that fate engraved♪
♪شفاء الجروح التي نقشها القدر♪
♪That light inside my restless soul♪
♪هذا النور داخل روحي المضطربة♪
♪One life to live, one final goal♪
♪حياة واحدة للعيش، وهدف نهائي واحد♪
♪I'll love with courage, wild and free♪
♪سأحب بشجاعة، بوحشية وحرية♪
♪Break through the noise, let them hear me♪
♪اخترق الضوضاء، دعهم يسمعونني♪
♪Holding tight♪
♪التمسك بقوة♪
♪The burning faith you gave♪
♪الإيمان المتقد الذي أعطيته♪
♪Healing wounds that fate engraved♪
♪شفاء الجروح التي نقشها القدر♪
♪That light inside my restless soul♪
♪هذا النور داخل روحي المضطربة♪
♪One life to live, one final goal♪
♪حياة واحدة للعيش، وهدف نهائي واحد♪
♪I'll love with courage, wild and free♪
♪سأحب بشجاعة، بوحشية وحرية♪
♪Break through the noise, let them hear me♪
♪اخترق الضوضاء، دعهم يسمعونني♪
=Dragon King's Decree=
=مرسوم ملك التنين=
=Episode 8=
=الحلقة 8=
Haven't you been wanting to leave the Feng family?
هل كنت ترغب في مغادرة عائلة فينج؟
Go.
يذهب.
Don't ever come back.
لا تعود أبدًا.
Feng Qingfeng...
فنغ كينغفنغ...
what's that supposed to mean?
ماذا يعني ذلك؟
Qingyun,
تشينغيون،
hurry.
عجل.
Get Zhilou back to the council hall.
أعيدي تشيلو إلى قاعة المجلس.
What are you trying to say?
ماذا تحاول أن تقول؟
Feng Qingfeng,
فنغ كينغفنغ
answer me!
يجيبني!
what do you mean by that?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
Surround them!
أحاطوا بهم!
Yes, sir!
نعم سيدي!
I, Lenghou Ye, head of the Lenghou family,
أنا، لينغهو يي، رئيس عائلة لينغهو،
have come to offer congratulations!
لقد جاءوا لتقديم التهاني!
You and your family aren't welcome here!
أنت وعائلتك غير مرحب بهم هنا!
That's some attitude you've got.
هذا هو بعض الموقف الذي حصلت عليه.
Do you honestly think someone
هل تعتقد حقا أن شخصا ما
with your martial cultivation can address me this way?
هل تستطيع من خلال تدريبك العسكري أن تخاطبني بهذه الطريقة؟
My martial cultivation is indeed beneath yours.
زراعتي القتالية هي في الواقع أقل من زراعتك.
For years,
لسنوات عديدة،
your family has pushed mine around at every turn.
لقد فرضت عائلتك عليّ كل شيء في كل منعطف.
I've put up with it
لقد تحملت ذلك
to keep my family safe.
للحفاظ على سلامة عائلتي.
But I didn't expect you to keep pushing
ولكنني لم أتوقع منك الاستمرار في الدفع
and go this far!
واذهب إلى هذا الحد!
Today,
اليوم،
no matter where my cultivation level stands,
بغض النظر عن مستوى زراعتي،
as long as I'm standing here...
طالما أنا واقفًا هنا...
I'm not backing down.
أنا لا أتراجع.
Fine.
بخير.
I'll give you that chance.
سأعطيك هذه الفرصة.
You can be the first
يمكنك أن تكون الأول
to join my son in the grave!
للانضمام إلى ابني في القبر!
You actually have four spiritual roots.
في الواقع لديك أربعة جذور روحية.
You're good at hiding things, you sly old schemer.
أنت جيد في إخفاء الأشياء، أيها المخطط العجوز الماكر.
But even then,
ولكن حتى ذلك الحين،
you're still no match for me.
أنت لا تزال غير قادر على مواجهتي.
How about now?
ماذا عن الآن؟
Six spiritual roots?
ستة جذور روحية؟
You forced your spiritual roots awake.
لقد أجبرت جذورك الروحية على الاستيقاظ.
Win or lose,
الفوز أو الخسارة
it'll kill you.
سوف يقتلك.
I don't need heaven-defying power.
لا أحتاج إلى قوة تتحدى السماء.
Standing guard over the people I cherish
الوقوف حارسًا على الأشخاص الذين أعزهم
is the greatest purpose of my life.
هو أعظم هدف في حياتي.
The sanctuary is on the brink of life and death,
الحرم على حافة الحياة والموت،
and you're here making a scene!
وأنت هنا تصنع مشهدًا!
Guards,
حراس،
take Zhi
خذ زهي
to the Tree of Life and seal him inside
إلى شجرة الحياة وختمه بداخلها
to reflect on his actions.
للتفكير في أفعاله.
No one's allowed to treat his injuries.
لا يُسمح لأحد بمعالجة إصاباته.
Shang,
شانغ،
your duty
واجبك
is to follow the Dragon King's Decree's prophecy,
هو اتباع نبوءة مرسوم ملك التنين،
inherit the Dragon King's throne,
وراثة عرش ملك التنين،
marry the Wujing Saintess,
الزواج من Wujing Saintess,
and protect the sanctuary.
و حماية الحرم.
Yet now,
ولكن الآن،
you first lost the sigil
لقد فقدت الرمز أولاً
because a human girl
لأنها فتاة بشرية
saved your life,
لقد أنقذت حياتك
then went
ثم ذهب
and married her in the mortal realm,
وتزوجها في عالم البشر،
and even handed her the Icebound Sword!
وحتى أنه سلمها السيف الجليدي!
You...
أنت...
You've truly...
لقد حقا...
disappointed me.
خيب ظني.
Father,
أب،
the sigil somehow formed a bond
لقد شكلت الختم بطريقة ما رابطة
with Feng Zhilou when the Yang poison
مع فينج تشيلو عندما سم يانغ
nearly killed me,
كاد أن يقتلني
and I haven't been able to remove it.
ولم أتمكن من إزالته.
I left her the Icebound Sword
لقد تركت لها السيف الجليدي
upon returning to the sanctuary,
عند العودة إلى الحرم،
all to safeguard the sigil.
كل ذلك لحماية الرمز.
The sigil is your reverse scale.
الرمز هو مقياسك العكسي.
If it can't be removed,
إذا لم يكن من الممكن إزالته،
it means you formed a blood oath with that woman.
وهذا يعني أنك عقدت يمين الدم مع تلك المرأة.
Unless she dies and her soul's destroyed,
ما لم تمت وتدمر روحها،
the blood oath won't break,
لن ينكسر قسم الدم،
and the sigil won't return to you.
والرمز لن يعود إليك.
Father,
أب،
Zhilou saved my life.
لقد أنقذت تشيلو حياتي.
I can't repay kindness with betrayal,
لا أستطيع أن أرد الجميل بالخيانة،
and I won't leave her to die.
ولن أتركها تموت.
So...
لذا...
So, are you willing
فهل أنت على استعداد؟
to give up the sigil and abandon
التخلي عن الختم والتخلي
your marriage to the Wujing Saintess,
زواجك من القديسة وو جينغ،
all for a human girl from the mortal realm?
كل هذا من أجل فتاة بشرية من عالم البشر؟
Will you just stand by while the sanctuary falls,
هل ستقف مكتوف الأيدي بينما يسقط الحرم المقدس؟
the Demons invade,
الشياطين تغزو،
and the world burns?
والعالم يحترق؟
Father,
أب،
I can't believe
لا أستطيع أن أصدق
you'd pin the fate of every living being...
أنت ستعلق مصير كل كائن حي...
on a single marriage.
في زواج واحد.
Do not talk back!
لا تتحدث مرة أخرى!
Father,
أب،
I'm only trying
انا فقط احاول
to protect the sanctuary
لحماية الحرم
and all living beings in my own way.
وكل الكائنات الحية بطريقتي الخاصة.
Kill Feng Zhilou,
اقتل فنغ تشيلو,
reclaim the sigil,
استعادة الختم،
and marry the Wujing Saintess.
وتزوج من القديسة وو جينغ.
Those are the only choices
هذه هي الخيارات الوحيدة
you have left.
لقد غادرت.
Father,
أب،
Zhilou is one of those countless lives, too.
تشيلو هي أيضًا واحدة من تلك الأرواح التي لا تعد ولا تحصى.
She's also the one who saved me!
وهي أيضا من أنقذتني!
Even without the sigil,
حتى بدون الرمز،
I can still protect the sanctuary
لا أزال قادرا على حماية الحرم المقدس
and everyone in this world!
وكل شخص في هذا العالم!
Uncle Qingyun,
العم تشينغيون،
what's Feng Qingfeng trying to do?
ماذا يحاول فينج تشينغفينج أن يفعل؟
Silly child.
طفل سخيف.
All these years, your father's done far more for you than you realize.
طوال هذه السنوات، فعل والدك من أجلك أكثر بكثير مما تدرك.
He may seem strict,
قد يبدو صارمًا،
but it's only to keep others from hurting you.
لكن هذا فقط لمنع الآخرين من إيذائك.
When the Lenghou family tried to come after you last time,
عندما حاولت عائلة لينغ هو مهاجمتك في المرة الأخيرة،
he had to discipline you first,
كان عليه أن يؤدبك أولاً،
so they wouldn't take the chance to go too far.
حتى لا يخاطروا بالذهاب بعيدًا.
Qingyun, promise me,
تشينغيون، وعد مني.
no matter what happens,
بغض النظر عما يحدث،
you'll take good care
سوف تعتني بك جيدا
of Zhilou for me.
من Zhilou بالنسبة لي.
Every time he scolds you,
في كل مرة يوبخك،
he feels awful about it afterward
إنه يشعر بالسوء حيال ذلك بعد ذلك
and always has me bring you soup and medicine.
ودائما أحضر لك الحساء والدواء.
Who gave you the right to use the family punishment?
من أعطاك الحق في استخدام العقوبة العائلية؟
I'm the head of the Feng family.
أنا رئيس عائلة فنغ.
Do my words
افعل كلماتي
mean nothing to you?
لا يعني لك شيئا؟
You're born unable to cultivate,
لقد ولدت غير قادر على الزراعة،
and yet you want to leave the Feng family
ومع ذلك تريد أن تترك عائلة فينج
to fight alongside the Dragons.
للقتال إلى جانب التنانين.
Some people are born losers!
يولد بعض الناس خاسرين!
Let's go!
دعنا نذهب!
Do you know
هل تعلم
how guilty he feels every time he sees
كم يشعر بالذنب في كل مرة يرى
you being called a loser?
هل يتم تسميتك بالخاسر؟
Do you realize you're wrong
هل تدرك أنك مخطئ؟
for bullying Zhilou?
للبلطجة Zhilou؟
He could only discipline Feng Yunqiao in secret.
لم يكن بإمكانه سوى تأديب فينج يونكياو سراً.
Perhaps that's why
ربما هذا هو السبب
Yunqiao resents you.
Yunqiao مستاء منك.
Mother.
الأم.
Is that you?
هل هذا أنت؟
He wishes he could see your mother, too,
يتمنى أن يتمكن من رؤية والدتك أيضًا،
but he's powerless.
لكن ليس لديه أي قوة.
Your father was harsh and distant
كان والدك قاسياً وبعيداً
only because he had no other way
فقط لأنه لم يكن لديه طريقة أخرى
to protect you.
لحمايتك.
He'd rather be the villain in your eyes,
يفضل أن يكون الشرير في عينيك،
but he's never forgotten
ولكنه لم ينسى أبدًا
that he is your father
انه والدك
and you are his daughter.
وأنت ابنته.
My father...
والدي...
Father!
أب!
Father, open the door!
يا أبتاه افتح الباب!
Please come in here,
من فضلك ادخل هنا
Father.
أب.
Feng Qingfeng,
فنغ كينغفنغ
I'll never oppose you again.
لن أعارضك مرة أخرى.
Father!
أب!
You're fueling this flame with your own life to fight against me.
أنت تغذي هذه الشعلة بحياتك لمحاربتي.
As the seventy-second head of the Feng family,
باعتباره الرئيس الثاني والسبعين لعائلة فينج،
I swear to protect it with my life!
أقسم أني سأحميه بحياتي!
Father!
أب!
Feng Qingfeng!
فنغ كينغفنغ!
Mr. Feng.
السيد فنغ.
(I let my pride get the better of me.)
(سمحت لكبريائي أن يتغلب علي.)
(Without Shang)
(بدون شانغ)
(and the Dragons,)
(والتنانين)
(I'm still the Feng Zhilou who has nothing.)
(أنا لا أزال فينج تشيلو الذي ليس لديه شيء.)
(This is who I am,)
(هذا هو أنا)
(and the Feng family is the same.)
(وعائلة فينج هي نفسها.)
Feng Zhilou,
فنغ تشيلو
no one in your family
لا أحد في عائلتك
walks away alive today!
يمشي على قيد الحياة اليوم!
You survived?
هل نجوت؟
Isn't that obvious?
أليس هذا واضحا؟
Fear is finally kicking in.
الخوف بدأ يتسلل أخيرا
Isn't it a little late for that?
أليس الوقت متأخرًا بعض الشيء لذلك؟
Without the Dragons' protection,
بدون حماية التنانين،
you and the Feng family
أنت وعائلة فينج
are nothing but dust to me!
لا شيء بالنسبة لي سوى الغبار!
Utterly insignificant!
غير مهم تماما!
Father.
أب.
I will kill you!
سأقتلك!
I won't let you...
لن اسمح لك...
hurt anyone in the Feng family...
أذى أي شخص في عائلة فينج...
ever again.
مرة أخرى.
Do you really believe
هل تؤمن حقا؟
a loser like you is fit to stop me?
هل خاسر مثلك قادر على إيقافي؟
My father never bowed to you,
والدي لم ينحني لك أبدًا،
and I, Feng Zhilou,
وأنا، فنغ تشيلو،
won't either.
لن أفعل ذلك أيضًا.
Nine spiritual roots?
تسعة جذور روحية؟
That's nine spiritual roots.
وهذه تسعة جذور روحية.
Zhilou is the true martial prodigy!
تشيلو هو المعجزة القتالية الحقيقية!
Impossible.
مستحيل.
Impossible!
مستحيل!
This is all bluff!
كل هذا مجرد خدعة!
Zhilou.
جيلو.
The phoenix isn't born dazzling
لا يولد الفينيق مبهرًا
but will eventually soar.
لكنها سوف ترتفع في نهاية المطاف.
Prepare for your rebirth.
استعد لميلادك الجديد.
♪Like fireflies flicker through wild grass, fleeting light♪
♪مثل اليراعات التي تومض عبر العشب البري، ضوء عابر♪
(Sky high, clouds light.)
(السماء عالية، السحب خفيفة.)
♪Like evening breeze that stirs soft hair in twilight♪
♪مثل نسيم المساء الذي يحرك الشعر الناعم في الشفق♪
(Southeast flows to the sea.)
(يتدفق الجنوب الشرقي إلى البحر.)
♪Like fleeting thoughts that surge and then unwind♪
♪مثل الأفكار العابرة التي تتدفق ثم تتلاشى♪
(One thought, all forgotten.)
(فكرة واحدة، كلها نسيت.)
♪Chance meetings fade, just empty rooms left behind♪
♪تتلاشى اللقاءات العرضية، وتبقى الغرف الفارغة فقط♪
(Breeze chasing the moon.)
(نسيم يطارد القمر.)
(A thousand miles of ice.)
(ألف ميل من الجليد.)
(Mind and spirit as one.)
(العقل والروح كواحد.)
♪Light as a feather, yet it sank an island deep in me♪
♪خفيفة كالريشة، لكنها غرقت في جزيرة عميقة في داخلي♪
(No thoughts.)
(لا أفكار.)
(No fear.)
(لا خوف.)
(Unpredictable.)
(غير متوقع.)
♪In that one moment, life's grip I couldn't break or sway♪
♪في تلك اللحظة، لم أستطع كسر قبضة الحياة أو التخلص منها♪
♪Leaving me lost in memories, small and fading away♪
♪تركني ضائعًا في الذكريات، صغيرة وتتلاشى♪
(I can feel)
(أستطيع أن أشعر)
(the power inside me.)
(القوة بداخلي.)
(This is your power.)
(هذه قوتك)
(It's yours to command now.)
(الأمر متروك لك الآن.)
♪Like fireflies flicker through wild grass, fleeting light♪
♪مثل اليراعات التي تومض عبر العشب البري، ضوء عابر♪
♪Like evening breeze that stirs soft hair in twilight♪
♪مثل نسيم المساء الذي يحرك الشعر الناعم في الشفق♪
♪Like fleeting thoughts that surge and then unwind♪
♪مثل الأفكار العابرة التي تتدفق ثم تتلاشى♪
♪Chance meetings fade, just empty rooms left behind♪
♪تتلاشى اللقاءات العرضية، وتبقى الغرف الفارغة فقط♪
♪You brought a wave that stirred a wild, restless sea♪
♪لقد جلبت موجة أثارت بحرًا هائجًا لا يهدأ♪
♪Light as a feather, yet it sank an island deep in me♪
♪خفيفة كالريشة، لكنها غرقت في جزيرة عميقة في داخلي♪
It seems your punishment was far too light.
يبدو أن عقوبتك كانت خفيفة جدًا.
My benefactor is in danger.
مُحسني في خطر.
I only wanted to make sure she was safe.
أردت فقط التأكد من أنها آمنة.
Enough.
كافٍ.
You've repaid your debt.
لقد سددت دينك.
Your ties with her end here.
علاقتك بها تنتهي هنا.
Now, you can focus entirely
الآن يمكنك التركيز بشكل كامل
on your marriage to the Saintess.
في زواجك من القديسة.
News just came from Wujing City.
أخبار وصلت للتو من مدينة ووجينج.
The city lord's daughter,
ابنة سيد المدينة،
Liluo,
ليلو,
carries the Wujing Saintess' bloodline.
يحمل سلالة القديسة وو جينغ.
In three days,
في ثلاثة أيام،
you'll go to Wujing City yourself and confirm it.
ستذهب إلى مدينة Wujing بنفسك وتؤكد ذلك.
You shall show no further disobedience.
لا يجوز لك إظهار أي عصيان آخر.
Yes, Father.
نعم يا أبي.
Don't waste any more time.
لا تضيع المزيد من الوقت.
The moment that human girl dies and her soul's gone,
اللحظة التي تموت فيها تلك الفتاة البشرية وتختفي روحها،
reclaim the sigil at once.
استعادة الرمز على الفور.
Understood.
مفهومة.
♪Like petals fall, gone with the clouds♪
♪مثل البتلات المتساقطة، ذهبت مع السحب♪
♪Like stars fade fast in open skies♪
♪مثل النجوم تتلاشى بسرعة في السماء المفتوحة♪
♪Like snowflakes melting softly in the evening haze♪
♪مثل رقاقات الثلج التي تذوب برفق في ضباب المساء♪
♪Like your fleeting glance that gave me one brief dream's grace♪
♪مثل نظرتك العابرة التي منحتني نعمة حلم قصير♪
♪Like fireflies flicker through wild grass, fleeting light♪
♪مثل اليراعات التي تومض عبر العشب البري، ضوء عابر♪
♪Like evening breeze that stirs soft hair in twilight♪
♪مثل نسيم المساء الذي يحرك الشعر الناعم في الشفق♪
♪Like fleeting thoughts that surge and then unwind♪
♪مثل الأفكار العابرة التي تتدفق ثم تتلاشى♪
♪Chance meetings fade, just empty rooms left behind♪
♪تتلاشى اللقاءات العرضية، وتبقى الغرف الفارغة فقط♪
♪You brought a wave that stirred a wild, restless sea♪
♪لقد جلبت موجة أثارت بحرًا هائجًا لا يهدأ♪
♪Light as a feather, yet it sank an island deep in me♪
♪خفيفة كالريشة، لكنها غرقت في جزيرة عميقة في داخلي♪
♪In that one moment, life's grip I couldn't break or sway♪
♪في تلك اللحظة، لم أستطع كسر قبضة الحياة أو التخلص منها♪
♪Leaving me lost in memories, small and fading away♪
♪تركني ضائعًا في الذكريات، صغيرة وتتلاشى♪